Sara L. M. Davis Collection on Tai Lüe Culture
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Sound Recordings
  - AU-P3 Burmese singer - popular music - Chye Ju Kaba. Undated. (Box 4, Sr 32)
  - AU-P4. Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna). Undated. (Box 4, Sr 33)
    Series Title: Minzu Yishu Zhi Hua: Minge. [Flowers of Ethnic Arts: Folksongs] Tai Zu Minge [Tai Ethnic Folksongs]. Changkhap with Tai violin.
  - AU-P5. Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna). Undated. (Box 4, Sr 34)
    Series Title: Minzu Yishu Zhi Hua: Minge. [Flowers of Ethnic Arts: Folksongs] Tai Zu Minge [Tai Ethnic Folksongs]. Changkhap with guitar.
  - AU-P6. Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna). Undated. (Box 4, Sr 35)
  - AU-P7. Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna). Undated. (Box 4, Sr 36)
    Series Title: Minzu Yishu Zhi Hua: Minge. [Flowers of Ethnic Arts: Folksongs] Tai Zu Minge [Tai Ethnic Folksongs]. Changkhap with erhu/violin.
  - AU-Q Ai Kham Ngeun. Interview regarding Tai popular music. March 1998. (Box 4, Sr 37)
    60-minute microcassette field recording.
  - AU-R1 Tai Love Songs (male/female duet/duels with erhu). Undated. (Box 5, Sr 38)
    Purchased at Tai New Year Festivities.
  - AU-R2 Tai Lüe group songs with guitar. Undated. (Box 5, Sr 39)
    [Taped over English course tape]. Purchased at Tai New Year Festivities.
  - AU-S1 Wat Ba Jie. New Year's Concert at Temple (9-10 pm) (1 of 3). Ma Ha Liang, MC. Ai Kham Ngeun, MC. Various singers. April 1998 (Box 5, Sr 40)
    Ma Ha Liang, MC. Ai Kham Ngeun, MC. Various singers.
  - AU-S2 Continuation of above (10-11pm) (2 of 3). April 1998. (Box 5, Sr 41)
  - AU-S3 Continuation of above (11-12 pm) (3 of 3). April 1998. (Box 5, Sr 42)
  - AU-T Ga Len. Narrative Song. Undated. (Box 5, Sr 43)
    Purchased in Burma.
    60-minute audiocassette tape.
  - AU-U Aini Folk Songs. April 1998. (Box 5, Sr 44)
    60-minute audiocassette tape. Field recording by community organizer for German environmental project.
    [NOTE: No AU-V assigned by donor.]
  - AU-W "Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna) Fengqing Atmosphere." 1992. (Box 5, Sr 45)
    Han language songs written and produced by Banna artists in Jinghong, sponsored by state government.
    Includes song titles and texts in Chinese.
  - AU-X1 Zai Sang Mao (Burmese Tai singer). Undated. (Box 5, Sr 46)
    Bought in Gasa shop in town center.
  - AU-X2 Zai Sang Mao (Burmese Tai singer). Undated. (Box 5, Sr 47)
  - AU-X3 "Heun mai." Undated. (Box 5, Sr 48)
    Housewarming songs from Meng Yawng, Burma.
    Singers unknown.
  - AU-X4 "12 Husbands, 12 Wives." Undated. (Box 5, Sr 49)
    Sipsawng paw, sipsawng mae - from Meng Yawng, Burma.
    Singer unknown.
  - AU-Y1 Ai Siang Zai [in Chinese] (1 of 2). June 1998. (Box 5, Sr 50)
    Interview regarding popular music history in Banna region, Burmese influences, cultural issues, sinification, language, and new popular music movement.
    Recorded in temple grounds - background noise of talk, work, chanting, music, drums, etc.
  - AU-Y2 Continuation of above (2 of 2) June 1998. (Box 5, Sr 51)
  - AU-Z Mae Zhai Yay (singer), Ai No (reporter), and Sara Davis. June 1998. (Box 5, Sr 52)
    Interview regarding changkhap singer's life.
    Ganlanba, Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna), Yunnan.
  - AU-AA Dubii Pat - Recital of sutra at Wat Ba Jie. July 1998. (Box 5, Sr 53)
    Pan Basangha. The Hunter's Questions.
    Dubii Sing field recording.
  - AU-BB1 "My Hometown is the Most Beautiful." 1999. (Box 5, Sr 54)
    Recording of Tai Lüe folksongs. Sung by changkhap.
  - AU-BB9 "Yunnan Minyue: Hulu Si" [Bottle Gourd of Instrument]. Undated. (Box 5, Sr 55)
    Titles in Chinese.
    CD. Commercial recording.
  - AU-BB10 "Music of Small Ethnic Groups in Yunnan II." May 1994. (Box 5, Sr 56)
  - AU-CC3 Tai popular music by Hsai Mae. Undated. (Box 5, Sr 57)
  - AU-CC4 Tai popular music by Hsai Mae. Undated. (Box 5, Sr 58)
  - AU-CC5 Tai changkhap epic "Nang Gin Bu" (Lady eats crab). Undated. (Box 5, Sr 59)
    From Shang State, Burma.
  - AU-CC6 Tai changkhap epic "Nang Gin Bu" (Lady eats crab). Undated. (Box 5, Sr 60)
  - AU-CC7 February 2001. (Box 5, Sr 61)
    Telephone interview in Tai Lüe and English with singer Hsai Hseng Mao.
    Recorded in New Haven, Connecticut.
    90-minute audiocassette tape field recording.
  - AU-DD1 Proceedings of conference on ethnic culture in Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna). Chiang Mai University, Chiang Mai, Thailand. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 62)
  - AU-DD2 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 63)
  - AU-DD3 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 64)
  - AU-DD4 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 65)
  - AU-DD5 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 66)
  - AU-DD6 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 67)
  - AU-DD7 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 68)
  - AU-DD8 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 69)
  - AU-DD9 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 70)
  - AU-DD10 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 71)
  - AU-DD11 Continuation of above. July 2002. (Box 5, Sr 72)
- Moving Images
  - Changkhap songs. (Box 5, Mv 01)
    Yi Guang's house. October 1997.
    Ganlanba scenery. Man Suan Man temple. November 1997.
    Jingha scenery. January 1998.
    60-minute Hi-8 videocassette field recording.
  - Ganlanba: Full Moon Festival. January 1998. (Box 5, Mv 02)
    Gasa: Ban Gong Mai wedding.
  - Wat Ba Jie. January 1998. (Box 5, Mv 03)
    Annual Festival to celebrate freedom of religion: parade, popular music concert, monk graduation ceremony, etc.
  - Wat Ba Jie: Monk graduation. January 1998. Temples. March 1998. (Box 5, Mv 04)
  - Jinghong Water-splashing Festival. (Day One) April 1998. (Box 5, Mv 05)
    Dragonboat Races.
  - Jinghong Water-splashing Festival. (Day Two) April 1998. (Box 5, Mv 06)
    Buddhist procession.
    Temple festival.
    Washing Buddha.
  - Continuation of above. April 1998. (Box 5, Mv 07)
    Rockets.
  - Monk promotion from "pa" (novices) to "du" (senior monks). June 1998. (Box 5, Mv 08)
    Meng Ham (Ban Ling), Ganlanba.
  - Sipsongpanna State First "Tai Regional Cup" December 1997. (Box 5, Mv 09)
    Competition - Tai language, popular song, concert.
    VHS videocassette commercial recording.
    See Folder 42 for photo documentation of this item
  - Tourist dance show at the Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna) Guesthouse. Binguan, China. June 2001. (Box 5, Mv 10)
  - Interview with Sara L. M. Davis, conducted by David Taylor (1 of 2). December 13, 2005. (Box 5, Mv 11)
    Mini-DV videocassette.
  - Interview with Sara L. M. Davis, conducted by Nora Yeh (2 of 2). December 13, 2005. (Box 5, Mv 12)
  - AU-BB2 "Tai Xiang Qing." Undated. (Box 5, Mv 13)
    Tai Karaoke with lyric sheet in Tai Lüe and Chinese.
    Published by Yunnan Audio Visual Production, Co.
    VCD. Commercial recording.
  - AU-BB3 "Tai Zimu Ge." Undated. (Box 5, Mv 14)
    Tai Karaoke featuring two older changkhap (Yu Guang, Aye Jian) and two younger changkhap (E Anu Xiang or Yu Wen Xiang and Aye Kham Jian) singing fusion.
    Tai Lüe changkhap/popular music - includes the song "akhala" or "Tai alphabet."
    Song titles and liner notes are in Tai Lüe and Chinese.
  - AU-BB4 "Taiyu aiqing gechu." 2001. (Box 5, Mv 15)
    Tai Karaoke features former monk/songwriter Khanan Lsang (was Maha Liang).
  - AU-BB5 "Poshui jie de zhufu." Undated. (Box 5, Mv 16)
    Tai Karaoke with titles in Tai Lüe and Chinese.
  - AU-BB6 "Wodejiaxiang zui meili." [My Hometown is the Most Beautiful.] Undated. (Box 5, Mv 17)
    Tai Nationality Folksong singer: Yu Wangnan. Liner notes in English and Chinese.
    VCD version of BB1.
  - AU-BB7 Untitled videorecording. 1998. (Box 5, Mv 18)
    Government-produced for tourists.
  - AU-BB8 "Xue Tiao Min Lu Wu." Undated. (Box 5, Mv 19)
    For teaching Tai folk dance. Liner notes in Chinese.
  - AU-CC1 "Tai VCD Karaoke Vol. 1." 2000. (Box 5, Mv 20)
  - AU-CC2 Tai Khun from Kengtung. Undated. (Box 5, Mv 21)
- Artifacts, [ See Folder 43 for photo documentation of artifacts in Box 3.]
  - Bamboo flute with metal reed. (Box 6, Ar 1)
  - Woven Tai Lüe cloth. (Box 6, Ar 2)
  - Bundle of 29 handmade wax candles. (Box 6, Ar 3)